Bún riêu cua is a traditional Vietnamese dish, originating from the Red River Delta in Vietnam, and is widely known both domestically and internationally. This dish consists of noodles (either bun rối or bun lá) and 'riêu cua'. Riêu cua is a sour soup made from crab roe, crab meat that is pounded and filtered, along with the fruit of the perilla plant, tomatoes, pork fat, fermented rice vinegar, fish sauce, salt, and green onions. Bún riêu is often enhanced with a little shrimp paste to intensify the flavor and is typically served with fresh herbs. This dish has a refreshing, tangy taste, making it especially popular during the summer, as it’s very cooling. Many street vendors in Vietnam sell bún riêu.
